### **TYE STANLEY**

Phone: (409) 622-5834 | Email: tyestanley090@gmail.com | Las Vegas, NV

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/Tye-Stanley">https://www.linkedin.com/in/Tye-Stanley</a>

Portfolio: <a href="https://tyestanley.herokuapp.com">https://tyestanley.herokuapp.com</a>

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/TyeStanley">https://github.com/TyeStanley</a>

\_\_\_\_\_

### **Summary**

Software Engineering industry has one of the best advantages in improving problem solving and developing skills. This experience has helped me understand in depth about how to become a successful developer. Proficient in and understand HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, and MySQL along with my Projects; Nibbler, Food Planner, My Tech Blog, Weather Dashboard, Note Taker, and Password Generator as shown in my portfolio. This position will be the best fit due to my ever-growing knowledge with excellent teamwork skills and attention to detail.

### **Technical Skills**

Front-end: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, jQuery, Bootstrap, Material UI, AJAX

Back-end: Node.js, Express.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Rest API, GraphQL, Jest

# **Experience**

Nibbler (August 2022)

### Front-End / Lead Developer

GitHub: https://github.com/TyeStanley/nibbler

Deployed: https://fathomless-peak-48299.herokuapp.com/

- Nibbler is an online social network to directly connect foodies.
- Gives a place to update and share different types of restaurants and foods. Where you
  can rate different restaurants that people personally add to the website.

Tools/Languages: JavaScript, React, CSS, MongoDB, Express, NodeJS, GraphQL

# My Food Planner (May 2022)

### Front-End / Lead Developer

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/TyeStanley/my-food-planner">https://github.com/TyeStanley/my-food-planner</a>
Deployed: <a href="https://tvestanley.github.io/my-food-planner">https://tvestanley.github.io/my-food-planner</a>

- My Food Planner allows you to pre plan a week worth of meals.
- It frees up the much-needed time from grocery shopping since it automatically grants the required recipes needed for a week worth of meals. What I've contributed towards this project were assigning each of my team GitHub issues along with myself making sure we reached certain check points and helping teammates when needed. On top of mobile responsiveness and bug fixes to the code.
- Tools/Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bulma

### Weather Dashboard (May 2022)

## **Lead Developer**

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/TyeStanley/weather-dashboard">https://github.com/TyeStanley/weather-dashboard</a>
Deployed: <a href="https://tyestanley.github.io/weather-dashboard">https://tyestanley.github.io/weather-dashboard</a>

- Weather Dashboard allows you to dynamically search any city for the forecast.
- Weather Dashboard accesses a weather API effectively using AJAX to quickly access and display weather information. Being straight forward and easy to use for everyone who wants to freely check the daily and future forecast.
- Tools/Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Weather API

# **Goldentail Logistics LLC**

March 2021 - April 2022

Business Owner located in Houston, TX

As a company, we develop, manage, and implement every facet of the business to sustain longstanding profits and growth for the company. Our leadership consists of a long line of family businesses and connection in the transportation industry for 30+ years.

### Responsibilities:

- Managed freight orders, assigning carriers, and negotiating prices to reach a minimum of 10% profit as a brokerage company.
- Communicating between Carriers and Shippers so that both parties are satisfied.
- Data input and proper documentation for every freight order.
- Effectively solved transportation issues within minutes.

# Humane Society-Southeast Texas — 2012 - 2014

Volunteer

Went in on the weekends to assist with animal care. Fed the shelter dogs in a safe and efficient manner and cleaned out their cages.

### Responsibilities:

- Monitoring the well-being of the animals from 8:00 AM to 1:00 PM. Including washing, feeding, and bringing them for walks outside.
- Successfully cultivated close relationships with aggressive dogs.
- Diligently taught basic sit and stay commands to more than 30 dogs.
- Helped more than 20 animals find their new loving home.

# University of Texas - Austin, TX — Certificate earned September 2022 Certificate in Full Stack Web Development Lamar University - Beaumont, TX — 2014 - 2015 Course Work in Computer Science Port Neches-Groves ISD - Port Neches, TX — Graduated 2014 High School Diploma

Education